

# **Richard Weston**

**Principal Cloud Systems Developer** 

**Phone:** +44 7738 276 354 **Email:** mail@riweston.io

LinkedIn: /in/riweston GitHub: /riweston

A Principal Cloud Systems Developer with over 10 years of experience in the IT industry. I have a strong background in developing and maintaining cloud-native applications, and I am passionate about cloud computing, DevOps culture and platform engineering. I am a strong advocate for automation and quality engineering practices, and as a technical leader, supporting and mentoring teams so that we all grow together.

## **Skills**

### I already know

Azu	re 4/	15	Goo	gle C	loud	4/5	Te	rraform	5/5		GitH	lub Ac	tions	5,	/5	Bash	4/5
Go	3/5		TypeScrip		2/5	Python		3/5	Kub	Kubernete		4/5	F	Flux			
Pror	nethei	us	2/5	Gra	afana	2/5											

#### I want to learn

Nix CUE Cilium Data Pipelines

### **I speak**

**English** Native

# **Work Experience**

# **Principal Cloud Systems Developer**

October 2018 - now

#### Cloudreach

Principal Cloud Systems Developer at Cloudreach, working with a variety of clients to deliver cloud native solutions. I am responsible for leading the technical delivery of projects, providing technical leadership and mentoring to the team, working with the sales team to provide technical pre-sales support and outlining a level of effort for the delivery of projects. Internally I work closely with the leadership team to support the growth of the business and the development of the engineering practice.

Technologies: AKS, Azure, Google Cloud, GKE, Go, Python, Terraform

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in my application to be processed for the purposes of the recruitment process.

## **Infrastructure Engineer (Cloud & Automation)**

April 2018 - October 2018

TFL

In my role at TFL, I was responsible for supporting the cloud infrastructure and automation of the Azure platform. I was responsible for building CI/CD pipelines and process to build IaC environments using Azure DevOps, cost analysis and cloud resource consolidation using cloud governance and compliance tooling, and developed Azure native automation tools using DSC/Runbooks/Managed Service Catalogues.

Technologies: Azure, Azure DevOps, PowerShell

### **Windows Systems Administrator**

March 2015 - April 2018

Rackspace

At Rackspace, I was a member of the Windows Systems Administration team in the enterprise support team. I was responsible for providing technical support for Windows Server typically hosted on VMware infrastructure. I also provided support for public cloud hosted on Openstack platform, health monitoring with SCOM and New Relic, and developed reusable Powershell functions for large scale execution across Rackspace managed services.

Technologies: Active Directory, PowerShell, VMware, Windows Server

# **Education**

## **BSc Computer Games Design**

October 2006 - July 2010

**Staffordshire University** 

Master degree. Specialization in computer games design.